All right, welcome back. Perhaps you
watched the last few videos and thought,
"Okay, you've taught me how to add,
subtract, multiply, divide, raise it to
an exponent, and even the modulus
operator." You might not know how you
feel about that one yet. Um, but you may
have noticed that I did not teach you
how to take the square root of
something. That is because I want to
introduce you to something called the
math library. So, the math library is
uh, so basically what a library is is
it's just code that someone else has
written that makes your life easier. You
don't have to fully understand how it
works. You just have to know that it
works. If you think about a car, you
probably don't understand all of the
complex chemical reactions that are
happening in the engine to make it run
or to make it accelerate when you push
the gas pedal, but you know that when
you push the gas pedal, your car
accelerates. So, similarly, in
programming, when you use a library, you
might not know exactly how it was coded
behind the scenes, but you trust that it
works and you can use it to speed up
your development. So, in this case, I'm
going to introduce you to the math
library. And the first thing I'm going
to show you in the math library is the
square root function. So if we want to
know what the square root of my number
is, then we're going to say alert just
so we can see the output of any math
that we do. And then we're going to
access the math library. To tell
JavaScript that we want to access the
math library, we have to use the math
libraries name. The name for the math
library is math. So you're going to use
a capital M and then lowercase a th. So,
you're just going to spell out math with
a capital N, and then you're going to
hit the period or the dot symbol. Um,
everything you see here is code that
someone else wrote that you just get to
take advantage of. Uh, so if you want to
take the log of something, um, if you
want to find
um the sign of something, you can see
that there's a lot of things the math
library can do. In this case, we want to
take the square root. So, the way we do
that is sqrt.
And then you'll notice if I mouse off of
it, it's a purple box. Anytime you see a
purple box, it means you need um opening
and closing parenthesis. So, I'm going
to put those and it says, "K, you need
to give me a number." So, I'm going to
give it my num because that is holding a
number. 25 is a number. We're going to
say, "Take my num, take the square root,
and then alert it." So if I save this
and
I go to my website, you can see the
square root of 25 is five, which is
exactly what we'd expect.